<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>syknapptic</title>
    <link>https://syknapptic.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on syknapptic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://syknapptic.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Tidyverse: Getting Your Feet Wet</title>
      <link>https://syknapptic.com/2018/03/tidyverse-getting-your-feet-wet/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syknapptic.com/2018/03/tidyverse-getting-your-feet-wet/</guid>
      <description>WorkflowResources Up Fronttibble%&amp;gt;%Sample Data“Tidy” Data{dplyr}select() columnsggplot() Exercise 1filter() Rowsggplot() Exercise 2mutate() Columnsggplot() Exercise 3arrange() Rowsgroup_by() for Grouped Dataggplot() Exercise 4summarize()ggplot() Exercise 5ReflectionImage credit to R Memes for Statistical Fiends

I recently had the opportunity to teach some tidyverse code to colleagues and classmates in a series of workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Shiny Apps</title>
      <link>https://syknapptic.com/page/shiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syknapptic.com/page/shiny/</guid>
      <description>recon : Really Convenient Spatial Data
 Search for locations by class or with a fuzzy name matching gazetteer.  Deep Learning Image Classifier
 TensorFlow-powered image classification.  North Korea Threat Finance Explorer
 A tool to facilitate access to DPRK sanctions data.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDELT, Missiles, and Image Collection</title>
      <link>https://syknapptic.com/2018/01/collecting-a-data-set-of-missile-images-with-gdelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syknapptic.com/2018/01/collecting-a-data-set-of-missile-images-with-gdelt/</guid>
      <description>----The Global Database of Events, Language, and Tone, or GDELT, is “a realtime network diagram and database of global human society for open research”. 
The potential for a firehose stream of global data has tantalizing possibilities for research, but concrete examples of work beyond simple evaluations of the database’s capabilities are notably absent…
See also:
My hasty walkthrough from November 2017, Evaluating GDELT: Syrian ConflictLet’s see how well we can scoop up a set of ballistic missile images using a combination of packages:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://syknapptic.com/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syknapptic.com/page/about/</guid>
      <description>body .main-container { max-width: 700px; }  Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Brendan. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in developing the data-driven insights required to fully enable decision makers.
Topically, my primarily focus is national security issues, but considering the wildly interdisciplinary nature of such work, I am constantly exploring other fields.
In the past, I worked as a security manager, combat medic, noncommissioned officer, linguist, and herder of cats. When I finally returned to formal academia, I developed a love for data analysis and programming.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>