<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R Bloggers on syknapptic</title>
    <link>https://syknapptic.netlify.com/categories/r-bloggers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R Bloggers on syknapptic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://syknapptic.netlify.com/categories/r-bloggers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>reticulate: Taking the Dragon for a Test Ride</title>
      <link>https://syknapptic.netlify.com/2018/05/reticulate-taking-the-dragon-for-a-test-ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syknapptic.netlify.com/2018/05/reticulate-taking-the-dragon-for-a-test-ride/</guid>
      <description>Should I learn R or Python? Despite the ninjillion articles and arguments dedicated to this debate, there isn’t a good, one-size-fits-all answer. But we have {reticulate}, so who cares! We can use both!
I started coding with Python. The choice seemed obvious at first. It’s a general programming language, so I wouldn’t be limited to only playing with data. Before grad school, I had never even heard of R so spending the time it would take to become truly functional seemed crazy, so I went for Python instead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Teaching R and Yet Another Tidyverse Intro</title>
      <link>https://syknapptic.netlify.com/2018/03/yet-another-tidyverse-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syknapptic.netlify.com/2018/03/yet-another-tidyverse-intro/</guid>
      <description>ContextReflectionResources Up Fronttibble%&amp;gt;%“Tidy” Dataselect() columnsfilter() Rowsmutate() Columnsarrange() Rowsgroup_by() for Grouped Datasummarize()Image credit to R Memes for Statistical Fiends

Considering this is a blog post, I’m going to get all bloggy here before jumping into the code.
ContextI recently had the opportunity to teach some R coding to colleagues and classmates in a series of workshops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GDELT, Missiles, and Image Collection</title>
      <link>https://syknapptic.netlify.com/2018/01/collecting-a-data-set-of-missile-images-with-gdelt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://syknapptic.netlify.com/2018/01/collecting-a-data-set-of-missile-images-with-gdelt/</guid>
      <description>----The Global Database of Events, Language, and Tone, or GDELT, is “a realtime network diagram and database of global human society for open research”. 
The potential for a firehose stream of global data has tantalizing possibilities for research, but concrete examples of work beyond simple evaluations of the database’s capabilities are notably absent…
See also:
My hasty walkthrough from November 2017, Evaluating GDELT: Syrian ConflictLet’s see how well we can scoop up a set of ballistic missile images using a combination of packages:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>